[{"topic": "Beauty", "question": "At Company ABC we have an important dress code for all employees. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Many organizations implement dress codes because they create a sense of unity for the customers. It also helps customers to find you when they need some help in-store. It is okay to ask about the dress code before you agree to it.", "\"I can understand why dress codes are significant for Company ABC. Can you tell me more about the dress code? I am happy to comply with any reasonable requirement when it comes to a dress code or uniform.\"", "\"In my current position, I wear a uniform. I am accustomed to this requirement and am happy to comply. I have seen your employees in their dress code, and I think it looks great!\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of effort into our branding. In your opinion, how do we stand out from our competitors?", "answers": ["Since you are applying to work for Company ABC, chances are, you enjoy their products and services! Take this as an opportunity to compliment them on what they are doing right! Research their website for any recent news, accolades, or product launches. Be sure to comment on your findings.", "\"I was on the Company ABC website yesterday and saw on your 'Social Impact' page that your company financially supports female entrepreneurs. This effort is a great way to stand out from your competitors since the majority of your buyers are female. To empower your customers is a genius idea.\"", "\"I find your branding to stand out because it's clean and you boast recycled packaging which many consumers value these days.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Judging by your resume, you appear to be overqualified for this position. What would keep you here, if you were offered the position?", "answers": ["Sometimes, hiring an overqualified individual can mean that they will leave when a better opportunity arises. Talk to the interviewer about why this position with Company ABC would be satisfying for you, long-term.", "\"I do have more years' experience than what you have outlined in your job posting; however, there are aspects of this position that would be new and exciting for me as well. For example, I would enjoy the exposure to more public service and premiere accounts. Despite my level of experience, there would be much for me to learn here at Company ABC.\"", "\"I agree that my most recent job title makes me appear to be overqualified for this position with Company ABC; however, there are many aspects of this position that will be a strong learning curve for me. I am ready for the challenge that this position would offer me.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "The beauty industry is very competitive. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Openly discuss with the interviewer why you want to work for Company ABC versus their competitors. Perhaps you have a friend who has worked at Company ABC, or it is your favorite place for all of your beauty needs. Keep your answer brief, and positive.", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because you have been my favorite place to shop for the past six years! I love your customer rewards program and the company culture is upbeat and enticing.\"", "\"In a competitive industry, I want to work for the best! I believe that Company ABC is the best because you care about the type of product you distribute and are well known for not testing on animals.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "We put great effort into being the best in our industry. In your opinion, what can Company ABC improve on?", "answers": ["Be sure to keep your reply upbeat, non-critical, and finish with a positive remark. The interviewer is looking for some light insight from you. Certainly avoid a deep dive into what you think Company ABC is doing wrong.", "\"I think that your company branding and in-store culture is exciting and upbeat. However, when I went to your website, it didn't seem to be as enticing as I was expecting. If I could make any suggestion, I would recommend lightening the tone of your main page. I'd love for online visitors to have the same great experience as those who visit in person!\"", "\"I have had great experiences with Company ABC so far and especially love reading your blog posts. My recommendation would be to post content more often. You have a very attentive audience, and I'm sure I'm not the only one who wants to read more!\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "How do you handle a situation where your supervisor does not properly communicate information to you?", "answers": ["You cannot force others to communicate with you in a way that you would always prefer. Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have handled a supervisor who does not interact with you in a way that you like.", "\"Whenever I have had a supervisor who does not properly communicate with me, I try to learn their style of communication and emulate it. Sometimes you have to relate to others in their style to be understood.\"", "\"I try to be independent and find as many answers on my own, as possible. As much as I would love to always work with supervisors who are great communicators, that is not always a realistic ask.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Tell me about your most recent visit to a Company ABC store. What was your experience like?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have shopped at Company ABC in the past and a brief overview of your customer service experience with them. Keep your reply positive and upbeat!", "\"I can tell that your customer service employees receive a great amount of training. I've always had a great experience shopping at Company ABC. My last visit, I was having trouble finding a specific product. As soon as I came across a customer service employee, they knew what I was looking for and found it for me right away.\"", "\"My last visit to Company ABC I made a huge purchase. Once I arrived home, I realized that in my rush and confusion I purchased the wrong shades of a few products. It was no problem for me to make the exchanges later that week. Your staff was accommodating and it made me want to continue shopping at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one-sided hunt. You must also feel as though this role with Company ABC is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer what your ideal employer looks like. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "\"My ideal employer is one that allows me to take the reigns when it comes to problem-solving. I like to be hands-on and prefer to work for people who value this in me.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Why do you consider yourself a team player?", "answers": ["Working well on a team requires you to have solid interpersonal skills and self-awareness. Interpersonal skills help you to communicate and relate to others. Having the ability to empathize, listen and encourage others are all interpersonal skills. Some additional examples are showing respect, being proactive and creative. Many of your strengths may also contribute to your ability to work well in teams. Self-awareness means that you know yourself well enough to recognize some of your flaws and areas you can grow. You also know what motivates you and what your strengths are. Share a few of your best qualities that make you a team player.", "\"I recognize that there may be days where I need to perform duties outside of my usual job description to help out. For instance, in my current role, I may occasionally need to spend additional time mentoring and coaching new employees to ensure they fit in with the team. This responsibility creates a tighter timeline for my other important deadlines; however, I see that the end goal is to create a well-oiled machine and that cannot happen without everyone being equally trained.\"", "\"I have always considered myself a team player; I enjoy the interactions and positive energy a team environment creates. My favorite team environment was at my last beauty salon. The energy was incredible, and I believe the customers took notice. I hope to create the same environment here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who have a true passion for the beauty industry. How do you stay up to date on industry trends?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have a genuine interest in this industry. Perhaps you follow a few beauty bloggers? Maybe you read specific magazines, or perhaps you even subscribe to the Company ABC newsletter for updates on new and unique products. Keep your answer brief and informative.", "\"I have a keen interest in the beauty industry. Some of the ways that I stay in touch with industry trends is by subscribing to the Company ABC newsletter and following The Beauty Blog online. I also follow a few great Instagram accounts.\"", "\"I stay up to date on industry trends through reading books, and continued education. Also, I have a mentor who has been in the beauty industry for quite some time. She helps me to stay up to date on new happenings in the industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "We take customer service very seriously at Company ABC. If a customer wanted to return a makeup product that had been significantly used, what would you do?", "answers": ["If you can research the return policy at Company ABC before your interview, it's a great idea to refer to their policies when answering this question. If you are responding strictly from instinct, be sure to think about what you would like to hear as a customer while keeping the profits of the company in mind. Affirm with the interviewer that you put a value on customer service.", "\"I agree that customer service is everything - especially in such a competitive industry. I know from being a customer at Company ABC that you will take a gently used product back in the first 30 days. I think that is fair. If a customer had used a significant amount of the product before returning, I think it would depend on the reason. For instance, if they had an allergic reaction vs. simply being bored of the color. I will always follow company policy and, if unsure, will call a manager for assistance.\"", "\"In this situation, I would follow your company policy and accept the return. From what I understand, Company ABC accepts returns, no questions asked, for the first 30 days.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Name your favourite Company ABC product and why it's your favourite.", "answers": ["Researching Company ABC before your interview is incredibly important as you want to be prepared for questions such as this. The last thing that the interviewer wants to hear is that you have never used their product or service. Assure the interviewer that you have a personal interest in Company ABC products and services.", "\"I have a few favorite products from Company ABC; however, if I had to choose just one I would say that is it XYZ. This product smells amazing, and I love how luxurious it feels on my skin.\"", "If you have not used their products before: \"I have heard many great things about Product ABC and saw from your website that it is a best seller. I look forward to giving it a shot!\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with formal training in beauty, makeup, or other related fields. Walk me through your relative training.", "answers": ["Your beauty related training may include formal courses or even on-the-job training. Likely this training is already listed on your resume; however, the interviewer would like for you to go into further detail. Be sure to express how your education will benefit Company ABC, should you be hired.\n\nIf you have related education/training:  \"I attended CMC Makeup School in Texas.  My specialty was SPFX makeup and body painting. This unique focus gives me an edge in the market because my creativity is tapped hugely. Also, CMC is one of the top beauty schools in the US so you can be assured that I come well trained.\"", "\"I attended CMC Makeup School in Texas.  My specialty was SPFX makeup and body painting. This unique focus gives me an edge in the market because my creativity is tapped hugely. Also, CMC is one of the top beauty schools in the US so you can be assured that I come well trained.\"", "If you do not have the related education/training: \"I do not have formal training in makeup and beauty; however, since I was a young teen, I would watch and try online makeup tutorials for hours a week. The beauty industry is a passion of mine that I have immersed myself in for years, so I do consider myself well trained and up to date on trends and techniques.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "At Company ABC we always want our customers to feel valued and welcome. If a customer broke a product in-store before purchasing it, what would you do?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can handle awkward or uncomfortable customer service situations. If a customer were to break a product in-store would you make them feel bad or make them feel like it happens all the time and it's no big deal? Assure the interviewer that you can handle customer service situations like a pro!", "\"Breaking something in a store is an embarrassing moment for customers. If this happened, I would first make sure that the customer wasn't hurt. I would then arrange for clean-up and assure the customer that it happens more often than they think. I would then ask them if I could help them find the right product, so they don't bolt out of the store right away. I would try to turn the situation into a sale and a happy customer who is sure to return.\"", "\"I would be sure to follow your company policy for moments such as a customer breaking product. Accidents happen so my instinct would be to ensure they are not injured and then safely clean up the mess. How do you prefer situations like this to be handled?\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "The hours at Company ABC can include evenings, weekends, holidays, and overtime. Do you have a flexible schedule?", "answers": ["If there are restrictions on your schedule, this is a great time to discuss those with the interviewer. Be open and honest in regards to your availability. \n\nIf you have no scheduling restrictions: \"I do not have any restrictions in my schedule. I am happy to accept any hours and would appreciate any overtime as well.\"", "\"I do not have any restrictions in my schedule. I am happy to accept any hours and would appreciate any overtime as well.\"", "If you have scheduling restrictions: \"I have school on Tuesdays and Thursdays from 8-4. I can work any other time though!\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "When were you able to resolve a problem within work?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are fundamental skills to possess. Display to the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace.", "\"In my most recent position we had a consistent problem with employees showing up late for their shifts or calling in sick at the very last moment. Rather than the typical documenting and reprimanding style that management usually takes, I decided to track the results of an accountability reward system. For 180 days, my employees received a reward for coming to work 10 minutes early. Also, for every month with zero sick days, a bonus was added. In the end, we awarded those with perfect attendance a $600 bonus. The bonus' cost us less money, in the end than the cost of lowered productivity due to absent employees. The program was a success, and upper management chose to keep it implemented for another six months. We will re-assess in December, but it seems to be working very well.\"", "\"As the Assistant Manager, I am resolving problems on a daily basis. The most recent resolution process I was a part of included a customer complaint about an allergic reaction to one of our products. I was able to resolve her concern by listening to her, apologizing, issuing a refund, and offering a replacement product. I am no stranger to dispute resolution, problem-solving, and creative customer service.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "When have you had to shift your priorities in response to sudden changes?", "answers": ["Have you been asked to change your priorities on a dime? How do you react to this kind of shift in priorities? Assure the interviewer that you can respond professionally when it comes to sudden changes.", "\"In my current role, our schedule is changed on a regular basis and always at short notice. I have been able to adapt very well to these frequent, sudden changes.\"", "\"I often switch from merchandising to customer service to employee training, all in an hour sometimes! I handle changes well but do understand that multitasking can come at the cost of productivity, so I do not seek out the changes. I do prefer to focus on my task at hand whenever possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "What are your career aspirations beyond this job?", "answers": ["Everyone has some dream or aspirations on where their career could go. When you think about the future, what comes to mind? Openly share with the interviewer where you'd like to see your job with Company ABC take you. Be sure to include how you feel Company ABC would fit in with those specific aspirations.", "\"I have some pretty lofty career aspirations, and after researching Company ABC and learning more about this position, I feel that this role fits with my future aspirations. I would love to see myself promoted based on my hard work and results, eventually managing a store of my own, then become a regional manager.\"", "\"I haven't thought of career aspirations beyond this role because this position is a goal that I have set my sights on for quite some time. The leadership component that you offer, as well as the continued education opportunities, are immense for me, and my primary focus at this time.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"In my current company, we have a very diverse group of people that range in age, race, experience, gender, and more. I embrace it fully!\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Outside of work, what type of creative activities do you like to pursue?", "answers": ["A genuinely creative minded person will have outside activities aside from what's happening in the workplace. Tell the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you express your creativity.", "\"Outside of work I like to attend dance classes and I also attend the odd paint and sip wine nights at a local wine shop. I also enjoy reading as a way of nurturing my creative side.\"", "\"I put creativity into everything that I do. I am really into fashion and design, so I spend a lot of my spare time helping friends to shop for clothes, pick out makeup, and decorate their homes.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Would your former or current boss describe you as a worker who gladly goes the extra mile to complete their tasks?", "answers": ["You can say that you will go the extra mile, but it's best to give a real-life example to the interviewer about a time when you did just that. Offer up your references as well and discuss with the interviewer what you feel your most recent employer would say about you.", "\"My former boss would describe me as an employee who goes the extra mile. In my most recent position, I was always available in my email, and many of my clients had my cell phone number just in case of an after-hours emergency. When you call my reference he will be happy to expand on that for you, I am sure.\"", "\"I am the type of person to spend extra time and care when it comes to task completion. I believe this is why I was promoted so quickly in my previous role.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"For the most part, I do believe that honesty is the best policy.  Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I would like to earn slightly above where I am now. Currently, I make $25/hour plus benefits and a 10% commission on all sales. My target income for the coming year is $65,000.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["Performance incentives can be very motivating. Talk to the interviewer about your feelings regarding performance incentives.", "\"I feel that performance incentives are a great idea. They keep an employee motivated to do a great job and ensure that they are on top of their KPI's. The majority of people are very enthused about being rewarded for their successes.\"", "\"I think performance incentives are important for driving people to get results. For me, as a manager, I feel incentives give me some skin in the game and get my team engaged in making an impact towards the company's desired results.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for answers to a few points when asking this question. \n\n1. Company ABC wants to know what kind of timeline is present before you are scooped up by another organization. \n2. They want to know how discerning you are with your job applications. \n3. They want to know the types of roles that interest you.\n4. They want to hear that they are your top choice. \n\nYou can certainly discuss your search but avoid giving too many details. Give the interviewer enough to satisfy the question without revealing your entire search. Some mystery is okay here.", "\"I recently started my search and had found some interesting job postings related to my makeup artistry education; however, this role with Company ABC is the position I am most enthusiastic about.\"", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\""]}, {"topic": "Beauty", "question": "If you were the successful candidate, how much notice would you require to give your current employer?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you plan to give notice to your current employer, or if you can start at Company ABC right away. It is always a good decision to show the potential employer that you would provide the professional courtesy of notice to your current place of employment.", "\"I would like to give my current employer the professional courtesy of 2 weeks' notice. I can begin immediately after that.\"", "If you have a vacation booked, this is the perfect time to discuss that as well. \"I am on vacation until December 27th and can begin immediately after that.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Do you consider yourself to be more creative or analytical minded?", "answers": ["Whether you consider yourself creative, or analytical - assure the interviewer that you are capable of providing both to the employer, if hired.", "\"I lean more towards being creative minded; however, I am very capable of being analytically minded as well. I feel this greatly helps me with my management skills as I am a creative yet well organized leader.\"", "\"I am more analytically minded; however, I do have a creative flair as well. The factors that make me analytically minded are my desire to get to the bottom of things. I am curious about process, and motives. I like to dig deeper than the surface of things.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Do you have any post-secondary education related to the fashion industry?", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your post-secondary experience. How has your education assisted you in your fashion-related career? You can keep your answer brief and to the point.", "\"I have a Bachelor of Arts in Fashion Design from U of V. This Degree has helped me immensely in the understanding of fashion trends, design, and style.\"", "\"Although I do not yet have a completed post-secondary degree, I have a completed certificate in Social Media Marketing. This knowledge is transferable to any industry, including fashion. I look forward to utilizing my knowledge in this area at Company ABC\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "If you were hired today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position it is important to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If I were hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If I were hired today I would place my focus where you have the greatest need. In my opinion, the biggest impact I can make is through being a dedicated employee.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "When did you realize that you wanted a career in fashion?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what led you to a career in fashion. Talk about your passion for the industry and where it all started. You can draw on some personal points but try to keep your answer brief and to the point.", "\"I have had an interest in fashion ever since I was a child. I would create outfits for my dolls and do fashion shows with my friends. My passion for the industry has been present from the beginning.\"", "\"I realized in my teens that fashion was so much more than just the clothes you wear. In 9th grade I did a presentation on the evolution of fashion. The research I conducted really opened my eyes to the statements that designers make through their collections. I was hooked!\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Tell me about a time when you made a suggestion requesting change in an organization.", "answers": ["In addition to being able to handle change, can you also recognize when change is required and be confident enough to present that to your organization? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you were able to make a suggestion for change in the workplace.", "\"Last year when I was managing dispatch for my company I noticed a pretty solid opportunity for us to save on overtime hours. I created a presentation and gave it to my manager who took it to upper management. The changes were implemented and I was very proud of the suggestion that I made.\"", "\"Our company did not have a strong policy when it came to workplace harassment and bullying. I was able to work with the leadership team to create a new program which has been readily welcomed by our staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations are to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000 and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Would your former or current boss describe you as a worker who gladly goes the extra mile to complete their tasks?", "answers": ["You can absolutely say that you will go the extra mile but it's best to give a real life example to the interviewer about a time when you did just that. Offer up your references as well and discuss with the interviewer what you feel your most recent employer would say about you.", "\"My former boss would definitely describe me as an employee who goes the extra mile. In my most recent position, I was always available on my email and many of my service clients had my cell phone number just in case of an after-hours emergency. When you call my reference he will be happy to expand on that for you, I am sure.\"", "\"I go the extra mile whenever possible because that's what great employees do! I have received very positive feedback from all of my previous employers.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "How do you manage a large workload?", "answers": ["Start off your answer by clarifying you never let a large workload stress you out. Each morning you review your tasks using a task manager application (if you do not have one I suggest google searching 'task manager application' and giving one a try). Continue to discuss how you complete each task by priority level and, before you know it, your large workload is completed.", "\"When I have a large workload on my plate, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a low priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I am able to focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\"", "\"I work best when I have a large workload because it keeps me active, keen, and attentive on the project at hand. I also use Trello to keep my team and I on task.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "At Company ABC we encourage our customers to create their own style. How would you describe your personal style?", "answers": ["Having your own personal style is very important in fashion. Talk to the interviewer about how you define your style and what it means to you.", "\"I would describe my personal style as 'sloppy chic' because I love large cable knit sweaters paired with leather leggings and a pair of great booties. My personal style is important to me because it's an expression of my mood on a day to day basis. It's how I can best express myself.\"", "\"I think it's important for everyone to have their own personal style and wear what they feel most comfortable in. If I could describe my personal style I would say it's ladylike with a touch of bohemian. My style icons include Kate Middleton and the Olsens.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "In your opinion, which designer has been the biggest fashion trailblazer in the past decade?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have a true interest in fashion and the ability to have an intellectual opinion on the happenings in the fashion world. Give your personal opinion on your favourite fashion trailblazer and back up your reasoning.", "\"I feel that the biggest fashion trailblazer in the past decade is Vera Wang. She is everywhere and her style speaks to people of all walk and budgets. I love that she can design clothes, wedding dresses, couture, and even home goods - proving that fashion isn't limited and is truly an art.\"", "\"The fascinating thing about the fashion industry is that there is no real one trailblazer anymore. Designers can make a huge impact when they are barely known, and sometimes the designers who are household names, have an 'off' year. At this moment in time, I feel that Tom Ford is the best known trailblazer because his style has remained distinct and consistent throughout the years.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Your current employer has a strong reputation in the fashion industry. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Discuss with the hiring manager the ways in which you feel that working for Company ABC will provide you with the aspects you are currently missing in your position.", "\"I have worked with Company ABC for the past 5 years and because they are a smaller organization there is no longer room for me to grow unless I were to relocate. This is why I am seeking a new opportunity. Working for Company ABC would allow me to grow into bigger opportunities while remaining local.\"", "\"I have had my eye on openings with Company ABC for quite some time. I have heard excellent things about working here which is why I am so excited about the opportunity to join your team. My reason for seeking a new opportunity is not out of dissatisfaction for my current company but more so for continued growth and career advancement.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "At Company ABC we have thousands of applicants per year. Why should we choose you for this position?", "answers": ["What makes you a stand-out candidate for this opportunity? Why should the interviewer give you the position over another candidate? Make your answer unique and memorable. Show confidence and don't be afraid to brag about yourself!", "\"You should hire me for this position because I can guarantee you that nobody else has followed your brand as closely as I have. I am passionate about fashion and see this as much more than just a job. Working for Company ABC would change my path and I plan to make a positive impact immediately.\"", "\"In addition to my recently acquired degree in Fashion Design, I also have a background in film. I am a world traveler as well. These 3 factors combined, make me an incredibly well-rounded candidate who will offer you a perspective and insight that others cannot.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Who is your favorite fashion designer and why?", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you follow fashion design by discussing your favourite designer. The more you can assure the interviewer that you know what you're talking about, the better your chances of landing the position.", "\"My favourite fashion designer is Ted Baker. The designs are classic yet bold and unique. I love the use of pattern. When someone is wearing a Ted Baker piece - you know!\"", "\"I am most attracted to the classic labels like Hermes and Balenciaga. They are true luxury brands that have remained relevant yet stand the test of time and tradition.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "At Company ABC we aim to be a step ahead of our competitors. In your opinion, what do you think will be the biggest fashion trend for next spring?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you keep up with the latest trends in fashion and that you have a personal opinion when it comes to forecasting trends.", "\"The fact that Company ABC is always a step ahead of competitors is one of the many reasons why I want to work for you. I love to keep up to date on new trends and think that this spring the trend will continue to be platform loafers, oversized trenches, and chokers.\"", "\"I admire that Company ABC is always a step ahead of the trends. One account that I follow regularly, to get a beat on what is coming up, is Nasty Gal. They are always a few steps ahead and at the moment I am seeing a lot of embroidery, cut-outs, and glitter accents.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Our industry is fast-paced, competitive, and stressful. How do you cope with high levels of pressure?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are capable of handling the stressful and fast-paced world of fashion. Share how you cope with high levels of pressure and be sure to comment on your ability to handle stress in previous positions. You can also draw on your references.", "\"I have been working in fast-paced, stressful environments for the past 10 years. When I am under pressure, my performance is the best. It's like a runners high for me. My current references will attest to my strong ability to perform under pressure.\"", "\"I handle stress very well and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure to not get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "At Company ABC we offer many areas of opportunity and growth. Where would you like to see your career in the next 3-5 years?", "answers": ["Everyone wants to see growth and opportunity in their career. Share with the interviewer the ways that you want to grow with Company ABC over the next few years. Assure the hiring manager that you are willing to work hard for growth opportunities.", "\"Over the next few years I would like to grow into a management function with Company ABC. I am willing to prove myself and do what it takes to get there.\"", "\"Ideally, 5 years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "How do you stay on top of trends in the fashion industry?", "answers": ["Fashion is always changing and trends change faster than any other industry. Talk to the interviewer about the ways in which you stay in tune with new and top trends.", "\"I stay on top of trends through reading high fashion magazines and browsing sites like Pinterest and Instagram. I also follow a few design houses and fashion bloggers on a variety of social media platforms.\"", "\"My favorite place to stay on top of fashion trends is Instagram. I follow a multitude of trend setters, designers, and stylists. I find it easy and fast to scroll through the feed and see what others are wearing, and talking about.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "The fashion industry is fast paced and unpredictable. Your work schedule may reflect that unpredictability. Are you flexible in your schedule?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are capable of working an unpredictable schedule. If you have any restrictions in your schedule, this is a good time to talk to the interviewer about it.", "\"I am happy to make myself available for work most times, including evenings, weekends, and holidays. I do have an evening course for the next 8 weeks on Thursdays; however, that is the only restriction currently on my schedule.\"", "\"I have a few restrictions in my schedule; however, I am happy to accommodate most days. I am unavailable to work on weekends but from my research I believe you are closed on weekends anyways. Could you share with me the hours expectations for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Tell me about your greatest work related accomplishment.", "answers": ["Talking about your greatest accomplishment will give the interviewer a strong idea of where you place your values. It will also show the interviewer more about your personality, how you like to be motivated, and how to coach you in the future. It is okay to brag a little bit when answering this question. Show that you are proud of yourself and your career accomplishments!", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This showed me that I am able to dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and be recognized for my dedication.\"", "\"I have many accomplishments that I am very proud of. Overall, I would say that my greatest work accomplishment is the positive reputation that I have in this industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "When have you had to adapt to change?", "answers": ["Being able to adapt to change in the workplace is a very important skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have had to adjust to changes on the job. How did you handle the change? Was it a positive reaction?", "\"In my current role there is a lot of turnover when it comes to our management team. I have had to adapt to 3 new managers in the past 4 years. It is not the ideal situation but I am able to adjust for the good of the team.\"", "\"Last year our company was sold to a competitor and a lot of our management team changed hands. It was a lot of change to handle in a short time.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Think about a difficult boss, professor or other person. What made him or her difficult? How did you successfully interact with this person?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you work well with most personalities even though you recognize there are some folks out there who are quite difficult to please. \n\nThink about that one person at work who is seen as hard to please. Perhaps there is someone at work who tries to intimidate others. Talk to the interviewer about what made this person challenging and what their relationship was to you. Avoid speaking poorly of anyone and be sure to end your response on a positive note.", "\"I once worked at a locally owned shop where the owner was very demanding. When the owner would walk into the store, employees would announce over their headset system that the owner was in the building, so that everyone could be prepared for his entrance into their department.  The owner had great intentions; however, his people skills were a little rough. I could see that he meant well, and I recognized that he wanted to do a lot of good things. When we interacted, I always took his feedback with the understanding that he didn't mean things as harshly as he might say them.\"", "\"I once worked with a peer who was very difficult in meetings and with interacting in groups of others. I took it upon myself to help this person interact better with others. When she would bark orders, I would reiterate what she was trying to say to the group in a more professional manner.  It took some time, but she learned to behave in a way that made people want to work with her.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "What career path interests you the most in this company?", "answers": ["This is where it is really important to have completed some research on the interviewing company. Be sure to envision where you can see yourself fitting, and growing, with the organization prior to your interview. Do some research on what a career path could look like with this particular company.", "\"What interests me most about your company is that there are so many options when it comes to career growth. Ideally, I would like to earn my way into a Territory Sales role, then a Regional Manager position. Eventually, a Director of Sales or Marketing position would be ideal. Of course, I understand that this will take many years of dedication and hard work.\"", "\"I am interested in a variety of paths with your company. I could absolutely see myself working in your sales and marketing department as I further my knowledge on your product and collections.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you apart from what is written on your resume. You are certainly not obligated to discuss personal matters such as your kids, or relationship status, for instance. Stick with a couple of fun facts to show the interviewer that you are a real person, too. Your answer should be unique so that you are a memorable candidate!  \n\nFocus on special non-work related skills or hobbies.  For example, you might share that you enjoy beat-boxing or making origami swans. Be prepared for the interviewer to stop you and ask you to perform your skill on the spot when it's possible! (This will make you unforgettable!)", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last 8 years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit.\"", "\"I am motivated and excited about this new opportunity because it will challenge me to grow in my (X) skills. I love soccer and enjoy spending time with my teammates. I am interested in continuing my education by studying (Y) to further my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "What do you know about our company culture?", "answers": ["Company culture and fit is a very important factor when considering a career move. Assure the interviewer that you have put thought, research, and consideration into how the company culture will work for you.", "\"I have researched your company through your social media channels, and on glassdoor.com. Your employees have really great things to say and overall it seems that you have fun while you work. I am looking forward to joining an organization, like yours, that is upbeat and thoughtful with an eye on helping the community at the same time.\"", "\"I know by reading your website that your company focus' on developing your employees for continued growth in the industry. You pride yourselves on being open, communicative, and friendly. I am really excited to work for Company ABC and find out more!\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"For my entire career, I have worked with diverse groups of people. I fully believe that diversity is not only important, but it should be mandatory. When we work with people different from us, we can learn so much!\""]}, {"topic": "Fashion", "question": "How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["Performance incentives can be very motivating. Talk to the interviewer about your feelings re: performance incentives.", "\"I feel that performance incentives are a great idea. They keep an employee motivated to do a great job and ensure that they are on top of their KPI's. The majority of people are very enthused about being rewarded for their successes.\"", "\"I think performance incentives are important for driving people to get results.  For me, personally, they give me some skin in the game and get my team engaged in making an impact towards the results.\""]}]